Serxhio Gugo iOS Engineer

(203)-819-1259

gugoserxhio@gmail.com

github.com/SerxhioGugo

linkedin.com/in/serxhio-gugo/

serxhiogugo.co

About

My name is Serxhio Gugo and I'm an iOS Engineer based in New York City. I'm a highly motivated CS student and Bootcamp graduate with 2+ years of experience programming in Swift.

I am fascinated by how mobile devices and applications influence our daily lives. I have always had a passion for iOS Development or technology in general. I have a good eye for design, seeking to combine innovation and technology to build quality products.

Education

Aug 2019 -Present

CUNY - BMCC

Bachelor of Science

- Computer Science
- GPA: 3.7

Experience

Jan 2018 -Present

iOS Engineer

Freelance

- Worked on many solo projects where my most noticeable one is on App Store called: Cinemator.
- Designed, coded, and deployed.

Sept 2018 -Jan 2019

iOS Developer Fellowship

BrainStation Bootcamp

 Completed an intensive 4-month project-based iOS Development curriculum designed by engineers from Facebook, Spotify, and Google. Topics: Swift, iOS SDK, REST API's, Persistence, Git, tech principles, culture.

Skills

I have been following Swift since late 2017 and have been working with it for over 2 years. During this time I have acquired knowledge on working with RESTful API's mostly using URLSession and Codable Protocol, Unit Testing & CI/CD, solid understanding of ARC, Retain Cycles and GCD. Efficiency in using OOP Principles, Auto Layout (storyboard and programmatically)

In-detail

- Frameworks: UlKit, SwiftUl, RxSwift, Combine, AVPlayer, Core Location, MapKit etc.
- Libraries: AlamoFire, SDWeblmage, Moya, Reachability, SnapKit, Facebook & Google SDK
- Design Patterns: MVC, MVVM.
- Communication Patterns : Delegate/Protocol, NSNotificationCenter.
- **DBs**: Core Data, User Defaults, RealmSwift, Firebase(Auth,Storage,Firestore)
- **Tools**: Xcode/Instruments, Git/GitHub, CocoaPods/Carthage.
- Design & Prototype: Adobe XD and Figma

Interests

- Self-Improvement & Business Books.
- Comedy, Sci-Fi Shows and Movies.
- Painting with Bob Ross.

Living in New York city allows me to spend a lot of time outdoors, exploring the city's attractions and catching up with friends.

On App Store:





CINEMATOR

- Movie Recommends, Trailers, Actors, Reviews etc. - Read the latest Entertainment news.

https://apple.co/2Uwc0Ni